A Finding Aid to the Burt Chernow Papers, 1930-2002, in the Archives of American Art AAA.cherburt
Archives of American Art
- Research Material for Christo and Jeanne-Claude: A Biography, 1930-2002; Series 1; 17.1 Linear feet Boxes 1-17, 23, OV 24
  - Transcripts and Subject files, 1959-1998; 1.3; 2 Linear feet Boxes 6-7
    - Other Subjects, by Name, Unedited (Box 7)
      - Imants Tillers, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 70)
      - Satcho Todorov, 1959; 1989 (Box 7, Folder 71)
        Contains a lengthy letter with information on family friends of Christo, and a 1959 photograph of Mary Hamzepour.
      - Calvin Tomkins, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 72)
        Research material only, no interview.
      - Harry Torczyner, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 73)
        Contains letters and photocopies of documents related to the Christos' legal matters.
      - Christian Tröster, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 74)
      - Audrey Tsui, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 75)
      - Jan Van Der Marck, 1981-1987 (Box 7, Folder 76)
        Contains research material.
      - Martin Visser, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 77)
      - Dorothy and Herbert Vogel, 1990-1994 (Box 7, Folder 78)
        Also contains clippings.
      - Wolfgang Volz, 1985-1993 (Box 7, Folder 79)
      - Jan Voss, 1990-1991; 1965 (Box 7, Folder 80)
        Contains editioned catalog from Galerie Birch exhibition.
      - Andreas Vowinckel, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 81)
      - John Weber, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 81)
      - Carole Weisweiller, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 82)
      - Masa Yanagi, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 83)
      - Mitko Zagoroff, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 84)
        Also contains photographs.
      - Anna and Jurgen Zech, 1995-1996 (Box 7, Folder 85)
        Also contains photographs and a letter.
    - Other Subjects, by Name, Edited, 1985-1995 (Box 7, Folder 86-87)
    - Other Subjects, by Project (Box 7)
      - Wrapped Pont Neuf, 1985 September (Box 7, Folder 88)
      - Umbrellas, 1991 October (Box 7, Folder 89)
      - Wrapped Reichstag, 1995 June (Box 7, Folder 90)
    - Christo Lectures (Box 7)
      - With Jock Truman at the University of Minnesota, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 91)
      - Sogetsu Hall, Tokyo, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 92)
      - Christo Talking to Students in His Studio, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 93)
    - Interviews of Christo by Others (Box 7)
      - Interview by Ann Stubbs, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 94)
      - Interview by Maurice Tuchman, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 95)
      - Interview by Robert Kirkland, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 96)
      - Radio Interview by Barry Farber, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 97)
      - Interview by Frank Gettings, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 98)
      - Interview by Anton Blitz, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 99)
      - Interview by Douglas Brooks, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 100)
      - Interview with Atanas Slavov, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 101)
      - Radio Interview by Susan Stamberg, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 102)
    - Transcripts from Maysles Brothers films, circa 1984-1997 (Box 7, Folder 103)
    - Questions for Interviews, circa 1984-1997 (Box 7, Folder 104)
  - Chronological Files, 1986-1997; 1.4; 2 Linear feet Boxes 8-9
    Chronological files contain mostly photocopies and seem to have been compiled by Chernow to organize information in the process of writing the Christos' biography. Files are named by the year in the life of Christo and Jeanne-Claude that they document, and they typically contain a chronology of events compiled from the Christo's appointment books, partial copies of interview transcripts, excerpts of Chernow's draft typescripts of the biography, and copies of printed material relating to events from that year, both in the lives of Christo and Jeanne-Claude and world events generally. Copies of material pulled from other libraries and repositories is mixed with copies of material found elsewhere within the current collection throughout the series. When materials have been copied from other sources, the sources are often not cited. Certain sources have been copied with portions interspersed throughout this series, such as the PhD dissertation of Carline Bouihlet on Christo, entitled Christo: Dialectical Materialism and Artistic Consumerism, a manuscript with annotations in red pen that is not otherwise identified.
    Among the chronological files are files for specific locations where the Christos lived or exhibited, files for the Christos' major art projects, and a single file for an individual, Peter Selz, found with the Running Fence file for 1976. The Peter Selz file is comprised entirely of photocopies made by Chernow from Selz's papers held at the Archives of American Art. Files bearing project names contain press coverage and documentation relating to the projects, such as engineering records, budgets, and travel schedules. These files are found with the date the project was executed. A file for Surrounded Islands (1983) contains the most primary documents of the project-related chronological files. Other notable documents in this series include Italian translations of reviews of Christo's 1963 exhibition in Milan and a photocopy of Christo's 1963 issue of the arts journal KWY.
    A complete set of photocopies of this series, made by Ann Chernow for Wolfgang Volz to aid his writing of the biography's epilogue, was discarded during processing.
    - Morocco (1956), 1986-1988 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Bulgaria, circa 1986-1997 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Vienna, Geneva, Prague, circa 1986-1997 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - 1957, circa 1986-1997 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - 1958, circa 1986-1997 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - 1959, circa 1986-1997 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - 1960, circa 1986-1997 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - 1961, circa 1986-1997 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - 1962, circa 1986-1997 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - 1963, circa 1986-1997 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Italian Translations (1963 Milan), circa 1986-1997 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Christo's Issue of KWY (1963), circa 1986-1997 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - 1964, circa 1986-1997 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - 1965, circa 1986-1997 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - 1966, circa 1986-1997 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - 1967, circa 1986-1997 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Air Package (1968 Kassel), circa 1986-1997 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - 1968, circa 1986-1997 (Box 8, Folder 18)
      Oversized material in box 24 (OV)
    - 1969, circa 1986-1997 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Valley Curtain (1970-1972), circa 1986-1997 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - 1970, circa 1986-1997 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - 1971, circa 1986-1997 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - 1972, circa 1986-1997 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - 1973, circa 1986-1997 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - The Oceanfront Project (1974), circa 1986-1997 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - 1974, circa 1986-1997 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - 1975, circa 1986-1997 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - 1976, circa 1986-1997 (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Peter Selz ( Running Fence, 1976), circa 1986-1997 (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - 1977, circa 1986-1997 (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - 1978, circa 1986-1997 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - 1979, circa 1986-1997 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Abu Dhabi Mastaba (1979), circa 1986-1997 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Gates Project Proposal (1980-1982), circa 1986-1997 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - 1980, circa 1986-1997 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - 1981, circa 1986-1997 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - 1982, circa 1986-1997 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Surrounded Islands (1983), circa 1986-1997 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - 1983, circa 1986-1997 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Pont Neuf Wrapped (1985), circa 1986-1997 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - 1985, circa 1986-1997 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - 1986, circa 1986-1997 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - 1987, circa 1987-1997 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - 1988, circa 1988-1997 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - 1989, circa 1989-1997 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - 1990s, circa 1990-1997 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - 1990, circa 1990-1997 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Umbrellas (1991), circa 1991-1997 (Box 9, Folder 19-21)
    - 1991, circa 1991-1997 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Over the River (1992), circa 1992-1997 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - 1992, circa 1993-1997 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - 1993, circa 1993-1997 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - 1994, circa 1994-1997 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Wrapped Reichstag (1995), circa 1995-1997 (Box 9, Folder 27-29)
    - 1995, circa 1995-1997 (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - 1996, circa 1996-1997 (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - 1997, circa 1997 (Box 9, Folder 32)
    - Oversized Flyer from Box 8, folder 18 (Box OV 24)
  - Notes and Writings, 1988-2001; 1.5; 5.4 Linear feet Boxes 10-15
    Notes and writings consist mainly of drafts and revisions of Christo and Jeanne-Claude: A Biography, written by Burt Chernow. Also found are later drafts made by editors after Chernow's death in 1997 and in the process of preparing the book for publication, and a proof and galley of Wolfgang Volz's epilogue, both in German.
    In a recording found in series 1.6, Business Records, Ann Chernow describes Burt Chernow's writing process in detail, providing an explanation for the unusual arrangement of documents in the early drafts. She explains this directly, saying he would type a small section and then re-type it multiple times, as a method of re-writing and editing. The arrangement of early drafts reflects this process, with multiple versions of brief sections of the text filed together with many annotations. These writings are filed in this series under the heading "Revisions." She also explains that he wrote and revised each section completely before beginning another section, and the arrangement of this series reflects that process. She also explains how Chernow created lists of words for each section to enhance his writing, and some of these lists are filed under the heading "Notes" along with writing fragments on Christo.
    Significant edits made after Burt Chernow's death are documented in the files named Posthumous Drafts. In her recorded notes on the book's history found in series 1.6, Ann Chernow recounts how during this stage of the editing, Jeanne-Claude removed all mention of her mother's Jewish ancestry before the manuscript was sent to the agent's editor, Tim Mennel. Tim Mennel made significant edits, primarily for repetition and length, before the manuscript was submitted to publishers. Correspondence between Tim Mennel to Ann Chernow is found with the edited typescript, and sometimes notes made by Ann Chernow regarding her response to his edits are also found. The first publisher, Kiepenheuer & Witsch in Germany, removed most of the material from the early chapters that dealt with other artists in Christo's circle in Paris and New York. Later the United States publisher, St. Martin's Press, added much of that material back in, cutting portions of Wolfgang Volz's epilogue to make room for it. Posthumous drafts document each stage of these changes to Burt Chernow's manuscript, as well as a proof of the German epilogue by Wolfgang Volz and its translation in the English edition's galleys.
    In general, writings for the biography are filed in the order of the production process, with Burt Chernow's writings broken down by his initial book sections, which were later changed. Chernow's working titles for each section are in quotation marks in the folder listing.
    See series 1.6, Business Records, for drafts of additional text generated during the publishing process, such as Jeanne-Claude's foreword, jacket text, various translations, and Ann Chernow's dedication. Business records also contain additional correspondence and contracts with the literary agent, editors, and publishers, as well as copies of all the Christos' approvals of portions of Chernow's manuscript. Series 1.7, Printed Materials, contains published versions of the biography. See series 2, Other Writings, for additional writings by Chernow about the Christos including multiple lectures on Christo and Jeanne-Claude's later projects. Note that Chernow's writing in the current series does not contain writings on the later projects due to his death before completion of the biography.
    - Lists, circa 1988-1997 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Notes, circa 1988-1997 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Drafts by Burt Chernow (Box 10)
      - "Early Years," Christo, Early Drafts, circa 1988 (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - "Early Years," Christo, Revisions, circa 1988 (Box 10, Folder 4-7)
      - "Early Years," Christo, Typescript with Comments, circa 1988 (Box 10, Folder 8-9)
      - "Early Years," Christo, Later Drafts, circa 1988 (Box 10, Folder 10)
      - "Early Years," Christo, Later Drafts, Corrected Typescript, circa 1988 (Box 10, Folder 11)
      - "Early Years," Jeanne-Claude, Revisions, circa 1988 (Box 10, Folder 12-17)
      - "Early Years," Jeanne-Claude, Later Drafts, circa 1988 (Box 10, Folder 19)
      - "Early Years," Christo and Jeanne-Claude, Typescript with Jeanne-Claude's Comments, circa 1988 (Box 10, Folder 20)
      - "Early Years," Christo and Jeanne-Claude, Later Drafts, circa 1988 (Box 10, Folder 21-23)
      - "Early Years," Christo and Jeanne-Claude, Later Revisions, circa 1988 (Box 10, Folder 24)
      - "In Transit," Vienna and Geneva, Revisions, circa 1992 (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Drafts by Burt Chernow (Box 11)
      - "In Transit," Vienna and Geneva, Corrected Typescript, circa 1992 (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - "In Transit," Vienna and Geneva, Later Draft, circa 1992 (Box 11, Folder 2)
      - Beginning through Arrival in Paris, Typescript Draft, circa 1992 (Box 11, Folder 3-4)
      - "Paris Years," Revisions, circa 1992; 13 of 17 folders (Box 11, Folder 5-17)
    - Drafts by Burt Chernow (Box 12)
      - "Paris Years," Revisions, circa 1992; 4 of 17 folders (Box 12, Folder 1-4)
      - "Paris Years," Typescript, circa 1992 (Box 12, Folder 5-6)
      - "Paris Years," Partial Typescript with Comments by Jeanne-Claude, circa 1992 (Box 12, Folder 7)
      - "New York Years," Revisions, circa 1993 (Box 12, Folder 8-12)
      - "New York Years," Typescript with Jeanne-Claude Corrections Regarding Plural Christo, circa 1995 (Box 12, Folder 13)
      - "The Seventies," and "The Eighties," Typescript, circa 1997 (Box 12, Folder 14)
      - Section on Anani Javacheff, Notes and Research, circa 1997 (Box 12, Folder 15)
      - Section on Surrounded Islands, Notes and Research, circa 1997 (Box 12, Folder 16)
      - Section on Surrounded Islands, Revisions, circa 1997 (Box 12, Folder 17)
      - Final Typescript Draft, 1997; 2 of 6 folders (Box 12, Folder 18-19)
    - Drafts by Burt Chernow (Box 13)
      - Final Typescript Draft, 1997; 4 of 6 folders (Box 13, Folder 1-4)
    - Posthumous Drafts (Box 13)
      - Pages Sent to Jeanne-Claude by Ann Chernow for Review, 1997 October (Box 13, Folder 5)
      - Pages with Edits by Jeanne-Claude, 1997 October (Box 13, Folder 6)
      - Draft Incorporating Edits by Jeanne-Claude, circa 1997 (Box 13, Folder 7-12)
      - Corrected Table of Contents and Footnotes, circa 1997 (Box 13, Folder 13)
      - Tim Mennel's First Edits, 1998 July 2 - August 11; 6 of 8 folders (Box 13, Folder 14-19)
    - Posthumous Drafts (Box 14)
      - Tim Mennel's First Edits, 1998 July 2 - August 11; 2 of 8 folders (Box 14, Folder 1-2)
      - Draft Incorporating Tim Mennel's First Edits, 1998 August (Box 14, Folder 3-6)
      - Martin West's Edits, Chapter 1, circa 1998 (Box 14, Folder 7)
      - Tim Mennel's Second Edits, 1998 August 14 - September 21 (Box 14, Folder 8-14)
      - Draft Sent to Publishers, circa 1998 (Box 14, Folder 15-18)
      - Ann Chernow's Notes, circa 2000 (Box 14, Folder 19)
      - Draft with German Publisher's Edits, circa 2000; 1 of 4 folders (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Posthumous Drafts (Box 15)
      - Draft with German Publisher's Edits, circa 2000; 3 of 4 folders (Box 15, Folder 1-3)
      - Epilogue by Wolfgang Volz, German Proof, 2000 (Box 15, Folder 4)
      - Epilogue by Wolfgang Volz, Typescript Draft of English Version, 2001 (Box 15, Folder 5)
      - Galleys for English Edition, 2001 (Box 15, Folder 6-8)
  - Business Records, 1968-2002; 1.6; 0.4 Linear feet Box 15
    Business Records include documentation related to the production of the biography, including correspondence, agreements and contracts, the Christos' approvals of the manuscript, and publicity. A sound recording on one sound cassette made by Ann Chernow recounts her husband's method of research and writing and the history of the book's publication. Also found in this series are price lists for preparatory works by Christo, which Burt Chernow helped to sell in order to fund his research and writing through an agreement with the Christos.
    Chernow's correspondence in this series is from his period of research and writing and mainly includes correspondence with Christo and Jeanne-Claude, and respondents to a research query for the biography published in the New York Times. Also found is correspondence with several literary agents. Ann Chernow's correspondence documents her process of seeing the manuscript through to publication after Burt Chernow's death. Her correspondence with Cynthia Cannell includes multiple drafts of the Christos' foreword to the biography, and correspondence with St. Martin's Press includes the English translation of this foreword as well as a typescript draft of Ann Chernow's acknowledgements and dedication.
    See also series 1.5, Notes and Writings, for correspondence between Ann Chernow the editor Tim Mennel filed with edited manuscript drafts.
    - Burt Chernow Correspondence (Box 15)
      - Christo and Jeanne-Claude, 1983-1997 (Box 15, Folder 9)
      - Anita Diamant Agency, 1997 (Box 15, Folder 10)
      - Linda Chester Literary Agency, 1994 (Box 15, Folder 11)
      - Research Queries, 1987-1996 (Box 15, Folder 11)
      - Regarding Surrounded Islands, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 12)
      - General, 1968-1995 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Ann Chernow Correspondence (Box 15)
      - Christo and Jeanne-Claude, 1997-2001 (Box 15, Folder 14)
      - Cynthia Cannell, 1997-2002 (Box 15, Folder 15)
      - Kiepenheuer and Witsch, 2000 (Box 15, Folder 16)
      - St. Martin's Press, 2000-2001 (Box 15, Folder 17)
      - Wolfgang Volz, 1999-2000 (Box 15, Folder 18)
      - General, 1998-2002 (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Ann Chernow's Description of Book History, 2002 August 26; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Approvals Signed by Christo and Jeanne-Claude, 1992-1997 (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - Contacts, circa 1986-1997 (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - Contracts and Agreements, 1988-1997 (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - Price Lists for Christo Works on Paper, 1980-1996 (Box 15, Folder 24)
    - Publicity, 2000 (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Printed Material, 1960-2002; 1.7; 1.8 Linear feet Boxes 15-17, 23, OV 24
    This series consists primarily of published copies of writings by Chernow, including articles in magazines and newspapers, books, and essays for exhibition catalogs. Also found are clippings about Chernow spanning several decades, and annotated clippings on subjects that interested him, such as arts education, writing, biographies, and public art. Flyers and press releases related to public appearances by Chernow and other events organized by him are also found.
    - Christo and Jeann-Claude: A Biography, First Edition (German), 2000 (Box 15, Folder 26)
    - Christo and Jeann-Claude: A Biography, Paperback Edition (German), 2002 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Christo and Jeann-Claude: A Biography, First U.S. Edition, 2002 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Annotated Photocopies of Articles, 1979-1992 (Box 16, Folder 3-4)
    - Business Card and Letterhead, circa 1995 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Calendar with Christo Reproductions, 2000 (Box 16, Folder 6)
      Oversized calendar housed in Box 23.
    - Clippings, 1963-1969 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Clippings, 1976-1979 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Clippings, 1980-1984 (Box 16, Folder 9-10)
    - Clippings, 1985-1989 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Clippings, 1990-1993 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Clippings, 1995 (Box 16, Folder 13-15)
    - Clippings, 1997-1999 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Exhibition Announcements, circa 1960-1981 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Exhibition Announcements, 1984-1995 (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Exhibition Announcements, 1998-2002 (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, 1961-1967 (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, 1970-1974 (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, 1977-1979 (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, 1981-1982 (Box 16, Folder 23)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, 1984-1989 (Box 16, Folder 24)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, 1992-1995 (Box 16, Folder 25)
    - Flyers and Brochures, 1978-1999 (Box 16, Folder 26)
    - Magazines (Box 17)
      - Art: Das Kunstmagazin, 1991 November (Box 17, Folder 1)
      - Art and Main, 1985 April-May (Box 17, Folder 2)
      - Denver Post Empire, 1996 September 8 (Box 17, Folder 3)
        Oversized magazine in Box 23.
      - Flash Art, 1977 May-June (Box 17, Folder 4)
      - Harper's, 1996 February (Box 17, Folder 5)
      - Max, 1994 March (Box 17, Folder 6)
      - Lufthansa Bordbuch, 1993 May (Box 17, Folder 7)
      - Savvy, 1983 December (Box 17, Folder 8)
      - Time, 1989 January 2 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Postcards, 1961-1995 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Posters, 1966 and undated (Box 17, Folder 11)
      Oversized posters in box 24 (OV)
    - Press Releases, 1978-1998 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Subject Files (Box 17)
      - Artist Biographies, circa 1966-1996 (Box 17, Folder 13)
      - Fabric, 1988-1993 (Box 17, Folder 14)
      - Negative Comments, circa 1986 (Box 17, Folder 15)
      - Reichstag German Material, 1994-1995 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Oversized Calendar from Box 16, Folder 6 (Box 23)
    - Oversized Magazine from Box 17, Folder 3 (Box 23)
    - Oversized Posters from Box 17, Folder 11 (Box OV 24)
  - Photographs, 1930-2001; 1.8; 0.5 Linear feet Box 17, 23
    Photographs include personal photographs and photographs of artwork and projects. Personal photographs include snapshots of the Christos' New York City studio from 1988, photographs of the Christos from the early 1960s through the 1990s, and early family photographs of both of their families collected by Chernow. Also found are photographs of Ann and Burt Chernow with the Javacheff's during their 1986 Bulgarian research trip, which began their research for the biography. Some of these photographs were used in the biography, and many of the older photographs are found in the collection as copy prints only, although some original prints are also found. Photocopies of some photographs found in the published book but not with Chernow's papers, annotated by Ann Chernow, are also found.
    Project folders contain a mix of official photographs of completed projects, photographs and postcards of project drawings, personal photographs taken during the project in the form of snapshots, negatives, contact sheets, and prints, and in some cases memorabilia from projects, such as Burt Chernow's access pass to the Wrapped Reichstag and a vintage photo of a Florida Hotel for Surrounded Islands. Several of the projects contain photographs of Christo, Jeanne-Claude, and other project workers on site with the projects. Many of the project photographs were taken by either Shunk-Kender or Wolfgang Volz, the Christos' official photographers. Also found are contact sheets of the Artists' Key Club event organized by Christo, Daniel Spoerri, Arman, Allan Kaprow, Roy Lichtenstein, and Andy Warhol in a baggage room of the New York City subway in 1965.
    Personal photographs are arranged alphabetically by folder heading, and project photographs are arranged with early drawings and exhibition views first, followed by works arranged alphabetically.
    See also series 1.3, Transcripts and Subject files, which contains photographs of many of Chernow's interview subjects.
    - Personal Photographs (Box 17)
      - New York City Studio, circa 1988 (Box 17, Folder 17)
      - Bulgarian Trip by Burt Chernow, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 18)
        Contains a typed list of descriptions of some of the photographs created by Ann Chernow.